Wade Gausden

0211101016 Dunedin wade.gausden@gmail.com LinkedIn - http://lnkd.in/TX JqB

Professional Profile

I'm an experienced software engineer with extensive experience in Microsoft technologies and working in the cloud (AWS and Azure). While my background is rooted in C# MVC/WebAPI web development, I've never been one to turn down the challenge of learning a new technology in 24 hours so a project can go out.

I'm someone that never stops learning, and I've been running a blog (https://dotnetcoretutorials.com) for several years, learning and then teaching about .NET Core. Through this I've helped both individuals and companies make the most out of .NET Core and transition from .NET Framework.

Tech Skill Set

Web Technologies	Cloud Providers	Database
C# ASP.NET Core	Azure (PAAS)	Azure SQL/MSSQL
C# Web API/MVC	AWS (IAAS)	MongoDB
AngularJS/Angular 8		PostgresSQL
HTML/CSS/Javascript		Entity Framework/Core
LESS/SASS		NHibernate
		Dapper
Other Technologies	CI/CD/Testing	Tooling
RabbitMQ/EasyNetQ	Azure Devops	Azure Devops
Elasticsearch/NEST	Teamcity	Git/GitFlow
		-
Ninject/Unity/Autofac	Jenkins	Github/Bitbucket
Ninject/Unity/Autofac New Relic/Raygun	Jenkins Specflow/Selenium	Github/Bitbucket Jira
' ' ''		,

Work History

Contract Software Engineer/Consultant

August 2019 – Present

- Moved back into the contract market to mesh my technical knowledge, people skills, and pragmatic mindset into a consultation role.
- 3 month contract extension with Provoke Solutions to develop across a range of projects from Microsoft Power Platform/Apps/Flow to SPAs built in .NET Core/Angular.
- 1 month contract with Provoke Solutions to do bespoke development on a sales info platform build using Squidex CMS, Angular Universal, NodeJS and Azure.
- 3 month contract extension with Silver Fern Farms to build a SPA self service portal using .NET Core, Angular 8, and hosted all in Azure PAAS.
- 3 month contract with Silver Fern Farms to ensure their legacy platform of VB6, VB.NET, and C# WPF apps don't fall over while moving to a more modern architecture.

Writer/Blogger - .NET Core Tutorials (dotnetcoretutorials.com)

December 2016 - Present

- In late 2016 I started a blog to jot down ideas around the newly formed .NET Core framework from Microsoft.
- Grown to over 120k monthly readers spread out across the globe.
- Use my experience to help companies make the most out of .NET Core and come up with transition plans to migrate from.NET Framework.
- Contacted by well-known companies to test .NET Core iterations of their products including Raygun APM, RevDebug, and NDepend.

Software Engineer - Timely

March 2018 - August 2019

- Took a leap and moved to Dunedin, partly to escape the Auckland property bubble, partly to jump on board with an exciting SAAS company in Timely.
- Lead numerous mini-projects around code performance, utilizing APM tools such as New Relic and Raygun, benchmarking tools such as BenchmarkDotNet and ANTS Profiler, and SQL improvements using Azure SQL Performance Tuner.
- Lead development on Timely's internal mobile API build on .NET. Enforced API standards such as proper use of REST, JWT Authentication and API Versioning.
- Architected and lead a team to build an integration between Timely and Zapier built using .NET Core/NodeJS.

Technical Lead - Provoke Solutions

April 2017 – March 2018

- My role at Provoke is a unique one where I split my time leading projects, fixing failing ones, and using my past product development experience to improve technical expertise and process within a bespoke software company.
- Technical Lead for a chat bot project for a large bank. Utilized Microsoft Bot Framework, Azure LUIS (Language Understanding Service), QnA Service, Sentiment Analysis, as well as various Azure compute/storage services.
- Technical Lead on a public web and customer self service portal build for a large utilities company. Built on the Kentico platform and hosted in Azure.

Contract .NET Software Engineer - wadegausden.com

September 2016 - April 2017

I decided to take a step away from permanent roles and take a look at the contract market. My primary reason was to taste roles outside of my Saas/Startup/Product background, and get a feeling for how enterprises, vendors and other types of companies work.

- 3 month contract with Bartercard NZ to build an online ECommerce Platform using NopCommerce in C#/.NET.
- 2 month contract with Geographical Business Solutions to build a web backend for a GIS Farming solution in AngularJS/LESS/.NET Core.
- 3 month contract to build a SPA Self service portal for Vector Power. Leading a team of 3 build on Azure Websites, Azure SQL, SASS/AngularJS and .NET.
- 3 month piece of work to help get various projects across the line for Re-Leased Property SAAS Platform (C#/.NET).

Team Lead - Unleashed Software

June 2015 - June 2016

- Started as a Senior Engineer but very quickly moved into a Team Lead role working on Unleashed's Inventory Management SaaS product built primarily on a Microsoft stack (C# MVC, MSSQL, Angular)
- Stepped into Team Lead role to lead the "System Team". The System Team is tasked with the heavy lifting of moving to a cloud provider (AWS/Azure), setting patterns for working with new technologies (Elasticsearch, Azure services, NoSQL), and other core functionality such as billing and deployment.
- Moved legacy applications to better utilize Azure PaaS offerings such as Azure Service Bus, Storage Queues, Blobstorage and Web/Worker Roles.
- Lead the drive for better CI driven from Teamcity and attempted the move to use tooling such as Chef to give us more predictable deployments and environments.
- Provided direction for development processes such as branching strategy, deployment processes, and team building.

Senior Engineer - Findly

October 2013 - June 2015

- Senior engineer working on Findly's suite of candidate sourcing SaaS products built using C# Web API as a backend for SPAs, but with many other non Microsoft technologies supporting it.
- Worked extensively in cloud environments such as Azure and Amazon AWS
 (Including the migration from Azure to AWS). Utilized cloud technologies such as
 AWS EC2, AWS S3, AWS RDS, Azure Storage Queues and Azure Web/Worker Roles.
- Large use of NoSQL technologies such as MongoDB and Elasticsearch, alongside traditional relational databases such as Azure SQL and PostgresSQL.
- Part of the drive for better microservices architecture with single API's being used for mobile and web.

Software Developer - Various (Magnet Design, KRevo, Bauer Media)

March 2010 - October 2013

- Got my start working on a variety of projects, most notably for Bauer Media, the largest magazine publisher in NZ.
- Lead developer for Autotrader.co.nz. NZ's largest motoring classifieds site. Built on .NET, SOLR, Endeca and MSSQL.
- Worked on numerous projects for Magnet Design with some of NZ's leading agencies (Ogilvy, Salt and Tango)

Education Diploma i

Diploma in Distributed Software Development Ames Training

2009

Diploma in Systems Engineering Ames Training

2007